Hello, everyone. Good evening. I'm Molly from CloudShanghai.
I'm very happy to meet you in the Academy of Sciences.
Today, I'm going to share with you how Cloud can actually teach you.
So let's get started.
First of all, in 2024.2, we improved the multi-tasking function of the GPU simulation.
Before this version was released, we were dealing with multi-tasking.
When we were dealing with multi-layered clothing, we used CPU simulation.
Now let's take a look at the difference between CPU simulation and GPU simulation.
In order to show the difference between the two simulations more objectively, I'm going to put the two software together.
The left side is GPU simulation and the right side is CPU simulation.
Now I'm going to open the simulation.
You can actually see that the speed of the GPU is obviously higher.
The speed of the GPU simulation is directly related to the speed of our computer graphics card.
There is also a difference in the speed of the different graphics cards.
Now I'm going to convert my simulation property to a test simulation property to calculate.
It is still used to compare the GPU simulation mode with the CPU simulation mode.
You can actually see that even in the test simulation mode, the GPU simulation speed used on the left is still faster than the CPU simulation.
The GPU simulation speed is still faster than the CPU simulation mode.
And you can see that the two simulations are actually similar.
Now let's move the fabric.
You can see that even if it is a multi-layered version, the GPU can still simulate stability.
So from the 2024.2 version, when we were making complex clothing,
GPU simulation was more recommended.
Next, let's take a look at the model.
Now we can adjust the model's shape, including the head, hands, buttocks, buttocks, chest, and so on.
For example, when making underwear, underwear, or yoga clothes,
we need to adjust the model's relevant shape when wearing this kind of tight clothing.
We can also adjust the model's back.
How do we adjust it?
We can choose this setting button in the settings.
Just open the model's shape.
Here we can choose the different size of the model.
When I choose, you can actually see a change in the model's chest.
For male models, you can also adjust the waistline.
So it's more convenient to make underwear, underwear, and so on.
In addition, we also added the software model function.
When making some tight clothing,
it is more convenient to see the pressure of the clothing on the human body.
Here I am opening a yoga suit.
Let's simulate it first and put it on the model.
Now we are selecting the virtual model.
Then you can open the software model simulation in the attribute editor.
There is a corresponding number value at the bottom.
The number just now refers to the model's fat content.
The larger the number, the smaller the fat content.
The smaller the number, the larger the fat content.
Then we open the simulation.
In fact, you can see that the model's waist will be squeezed in.
We can hide this template to see it more clearly.
If you are making underwear,
you can also see the movement of the chest when you simulate it.
Then we start to make clothes.
For students in the clothing industry,
or students in the clothing industry,
they don't know much about the structure of the board.
Then you can use the board generator to assist in the design presentation.
We select the 2D board in the main menu.
Board generator.
At present, we can generate T-shirts, pants, shorts, and shorts.
There are many ways to generate.
First, we can use the size table to generate.
Here we select T-shirt.
Then select its sleeve type.
The corresponding size table will appear at the bottom.
We can modify the corresponding size according to the style demand.
For example, the front length.
We can modify its value here.
When you modify it, you can find that the 2D window
will actually change our board according to our value.
We can also set whether the board is left and right,
and left and right.
In addition to supporting manual input data,
we also support the insertion of the Excel format table.
After selecting,
the value here will automatically fill in according to the input in the table.
Click the create button at the bottom,
and you can create this T-shirt.
Method 2.
We can use the AI function.
Find the AI version of the generator button.
You can.
We can use the prompt or picture to create here.
Here I create a skirt.
Select the type as a half skirt.
Then select it as a round skirt or an A-shaped skirt.
At the bottom, you can input manual input keywords.
Of course, we also provide some keywords.
You can choose.
You can also choose.
Of course, you can also use the form of the picture.
Click upload.
We can upload a picture.
Then click start generation.
You can see the size table next to it
will generate the size of this skirt.
If there is something that is not very satisfied with the size,
we can also adjust it again.
For example, I want to adjust the length of its bottom.
We can reduce it a little bit.
After completion, click create.
After the creation is complete,
we can take a look at our 3D window.
You can see that the automatically generated version
will automatically arrange around the model
and complete the automatic sewing.
We open the simulation.
You can see that these two clothes are simulated.
OK.
After our basic version is made,
you can adjust some adjustments to our version according to the design.
For example, I want to add two sleeves at the bottom of this top shirt.
First of all, we can use the straight line tool
to determine the position where we need to add sleeves.
Then select Add Seam on the straight line.
Set the width and length of our sleeves, etc. values.
You can also use the curve to make this seam
so that this seam is in the original state after closing.
OK.
We also do the same operation in the back.
In this way,
we have completed the creation of these two seams.
And the seam we created can automatically complete the sewing.
OK.
Now I want to put my skirt and clothes together
and make a dress skirt.
First of all, adjust the position of the bottom skirt
and move it up a little bit.
Through the side,
you can actually see our top shirt and skirt.
They have a relatively large distance between them.
Then we select the bottom of the skirt
and make it a little longer.
Then adjust the shape of our whole bottom skirt.
Make it a little bit smoother.
Then finally,
we just sew this bottom with our skirt waist plate together.
Then the simulation is complete.
You can see that it has now become a dress skirt.
Now I want to divide my skirt.
We just need to select the bottom line
and then use the internal line tool
to make it into a division line.
Enter a certain distance.
Then tie it tightly.
Now you can see that it has become a top and bottom two pieces.
Then we can also use this extension tool
to adjust our bottom skirt
to a shape like this.
OK.
Then you can see that our bottom skirt
has now become a dress skirt.
OK.
Then I hope my bottom skirt
looks more layered.
Then we can use the colon layer tool
to make multiple layers.
By adjusting the seam line to it,
you can complete this multi-layer design.
Now the two layers inside and outside
are actually equal.
It doesn't look very layered yet.
We can lengthen the inner layer
and then we can get an extra layer.
Then we can get a design
that is long inside and short outside.
Here we hide our inner line
and the basic line.
You can see it more clearly.
OK.
Then our skirt is complete.
Finally,
we can lengthen our sleeves.
Then we can lengthen our sleeves.
Then adjust the position of the sleeves.
OK.
Then our whole design is complete.
Next, we will apply fabric to our clothes.
As you all know,
there are a lot of fabric materials
that can be used
on the inside of the pants
and on the top of our pants.
You can choose to download
these materials yourself.
If we actually have a target fabric
in our hands,
we can use our Cloud5 function
to select Cloud5 from the object window.
Change to physical properties.
Then here,
select our corresponding fabric type.
Then enter our fabric ingredients,
fabric weight,
and fabric thickness,
and other relevant information.
Then the system will automatically
match all the information we just entered
in the big data
with a piece of mirror fabric.
This can greatly reduce
the time it takes
for us to search for
suitable digital fabrics
in a large database.
Of course,
we have included some similar text
patterns in our eyes,
which can be selected.
After selecting,
we click on the application
button to close.
OK,
then we apply this fabric
to the position of our bottom
and side.
We also apply
a suitable fabric
to the sound.
Finally,
we change the model's posture
to a vertical position
and put your arms down.
Before I change the clothing,
I want to make such a
honeycomb and flower pattern design
for my bottom.
It's actually very simple.
Just select our bottom
and select elasticity.
Give it a relatively large elasticity,
it will be fine.
Now it may not be very obvious.
Let's improve the quality of the clothing.
OK,
let's simulate it.
Now our whole clothing
details are complete.
In this way,
we can simply
change the version
and use the material
to complete a whole design.
In addition,
we can use the Kuli
and Konaid
positions,
we also have an
AI position generator
to generate a position.
In the main menu,
select the virtual model
AI position generator.
OK,
there are also two methods here.
You can input a hint
or upload a target picture.
Here I choose to upload a picture.
Then select the corresponding gender
as a woman on the top.
Click to start creating.
Then we can see
that the model position
has been created
in the three-dimensional window.
After the creation is complete,
we can also
make some adjustments to it.
All you need to do
is to use our model
tool.
For example,
I want to put it
in the upper half of the body
and put it straight.
After that,
we can save
this position.
Then save it
and put it
in the appropriate folder.
OK,
we can use
this position
we just created.
Just open it
and click OK.
Then you can see
that this is the position
we just created.
Of course,
we can also
rotate this position
left and right.
OK,
let's open a set of clothes
and use the position
we just saved.
Drag this position folder
in.
Now I want to
add a dresser
in front of this chest coat.
We are now
putting this chest coat
in front of it
because it is
connected to it.
So we are now
dividing it.
In order to
stabilize our dresser
later,
we can first
freeze this dresser
or reverse it.
OK,
then we use
the inner circle tool
to make a hole
on the panel.
We can make a circle
and use the rest
to paste it.
Then we can
turn these circles
into
holes.
Because we want to
wear a dresser,
we now need
some holes.
OK,
after turning into
holes,
we will start
to wear a dresser.
Before,
we needed to
wear a dresser manually.
The whole process
will be more complicated
and time-consuming.
In 2026.0,
we released a new
tool called
the belt
dresser.
Then we just
need to set
the direction of
the hole
to easily
achieve the effect
of the belt.
For example,
you can press
the left button
to select
the hole
in the 2D window
or the 3D window.
During the selection process,
you can actually
observe that
in the 2D window,
there will be
corresponding arrows
between each hole.
This is the direction
of the belt.
After the selection is complete,
we press
the return button.
You can see
that our belt
is finished here.
Finally,
we actually
just need to adjust
the looseness
of the belt.
Before adjusting,
we can adjust
the whole
looseness of the belt.
OK.
Then adjust it.
Then we can
put this
last
belt
tail
together.
We can
sew it together.
Of course,
you can also
just
pull it
naturally.
These effects
are all possible.
For the
sewing,
we just
sew
two internal lines
and then
sew it together.
You can see that
in fact,
the whole process
is very fast.
It greatly saves
our production time.
OK.
Then we will
finish
the sound
part.
Next,
I want to add
a print
to my skirt.
Before that,
we needed
to make
the fabric
in PS.
Now,
we can
actually
complete
our
four-way
production
directly
in CLO.
First of all,
we can
choose
CLO5
at the
bottom
of the
window.
We can also
choose
this fabric
for the first
time.
Next,
choose
its three
small
points
as
texture
properties.
Then
open
the picture
and
choose
the corresponding
texture.
Next,
we can
select
the
texture
properties.
And
click
Next.
Now we can
see
the
texture
properties.
Next,
we can
select
the
texture
properties.
Then,
we can
select
the
texture
properties.
Next,
we can
choose
the
texture
We can also use this texture editing tool to adjust the position a little bit, and then we can click on the application and close it when we are done.
OK, when our square continuous is completed, we can also automatically generate the PBR picture we need in the software.
For example, we can just click on the auto-generate button on our發現 picture.
In addition to the發現 picture, we can also automatically generate all the PBR pictures we need, such as our hallucination picture, transparent picture, metal picture, and so on.
OK, now we can match this costume with a mobile phone bag to make the overall look even better.
Then we can directly import a document from the bag we made before.
OK, as you can see, the whole bag is actually a bit bigger for our overall look.
Then we need to make the size of the whole bag smaller.
In the past, after we adjusted the size of the board, we needed to manually correct the position of the board and the overall shape.
The whole process is quite complicated.
In the 2026.0 version, we can directly search for its 2D board.
Then its 3D...
The overall shape of the 3D board can still be maintained.
We just need to select this board, and then we can adjust its size.
As you can see in the 3D window, the whole bag will only become smaller.
Its overall shape remains the same.
After adjusting the size, we put it on our model's hand.
As you can see, no matter how many times we adjust the size, or how many times we adjust the outline,
it can effectively prevent our costume from changing.
As a result, it saves us a lot of time to adjust it repeatedly.
OK, after the costume adjustment is complete, we can match a more suitable overall style of shoes and hair to our model.
We can directly select it in the library.
We are done with this costume.
Next, I want to add some background to it.
First, let's change the color of the bag.
And shoes.
Because it is black now, it doesn't look very coordinated.
I want to change it to a more matching purple tone.
Just change the color of the bag.
Now, let's add a background to it.
The background of the flower.
OK, you can see that the whole flower is made of board.
Then, by copying and pasting the board,
you can place it in different places in the window.
You can achieve this effect.
Then, we can add a wind controller to it.
Adjust the position of the wind controller.
You can also use the positioning ball to adjust the direction of the wind blowing.
Adjust a little.
OK, including we can change the intensity of the wind.
We change it to a little bit smaller.
This is the effect of the wind.
In order to say that our simulation is stable,
it is to reduce our computing.
We need to let our overall shape to freeze or anti-evaporate it.
Just simulate this petal.
Then open the simulation.
You can see that actually this petal will fall down slowly.
If you think the wind is too weak, you can make it a little bit bigger
I think the petals are a little bit too small
You can add more petals in the form of duplicating or continuous insertion
Then our whole background looks more layered
OK, then we can enter the animation editor
I want to record a flower petal floating animation later
Then we still keep our overall costume is frozen or anti-activated
Let our simulation calculation be a little bit smaller
After the setting is complete, the top is the progress bar of our playback
You can follow your own needs to make it longer or shorter
After the setting is complete, we click to start recording
OK, then you can see the animation effect of the flower petal falling in the progress bar below
After the recording is complete, we can change it to real-time
Look at the overall effect
If you are not satisfied, you can delete it and re-record it
These are all possible
After the recording is complete, I want to add an animation of the flower petal changing
We can add animation and then add the key point of the flower petal
Change the different flowers
For example, I will change a flower petal in the first point
Add a key point
Then we pull the playback progress bar back
Then switch to the second color
Then we can change the transition effect of these two key points
Play can take a look
In addition, we can also add some
For example, lighting, panels, accessories, virtual models, etc.
These key point animations
And then make different animation effects
Of course, we can also increase the image quality of the camera
In the drawing, we actually built in some camera animation
You can add it directly
Click to play
You can see the image quality of the camera
Maybe this camera is not very suitable for our whole clothes
But we can adjust it more
Then we can show this camera path here
Take a look at the adjustment
Then we can adjust the whole key point
For example, I don't think the first point is very good
Then we can move it out a little bit
Of course, we can also choose them directly and delete it
These are all possible
If you choose, you can delete it by pressing the fold button directly
Let's adjust the position of the first point again
In addition, we can also choose the appropriate key point from the back
Put it in front of it for use
For example, I think this section of the effect is okay
Then I will select the section I want to choose
Put it in front of it
Then move these key points in front of it to the back
Then click play
You can see the effect of this camera here
OK, of course, you can also customize the entire camera path
After the setting is complete
We can output an animation like this
Then I can show you the effect of the entire animation
Through our setting
Through our setting for the key point
Can be reduced
Need to be in the third-party software
The editing work in the software
OK, some students may not know about the version at all
But he is very interested in clothing design
So these simple modifications are also quite complicated for them
In the version of 2026.0
We have launched the virtual model 3D pen line sketch
This function
Then we only need to draw grass on the model
You can actually convert it to 3D
Convert it into 3D clothing
OK, now I choose this tool
I want to draw a chain
Then we only need to use this tool
In the window of 3D
Just draw my idea out
Now its side wind
I am now drawing a straight line
But I want to turn it into one
Stick to the human body curve
Then we can use this rubber brush tool
Wipe this line off
Then re-draw it
That's it
Then if we want to draw a chain
In addition
For example, I want to add some seam lines
We are the same
Can directly do a painting here
After switching to the reverse
Our method is the same
So the painting is finished
Click on the transition to 3D pen
It's OK
So that's how we just carried these lines
It can be converted into 3D pen
Then we can use 3D pen
and adjust it to these points.
As you can see,
some of the points are actually in the air.
From the 2025.1 version,
we can create this 3D pen in the air by pressing the P key.
This point is actually on the model,
so we just need to press the P key and select this point,
and drag it to turn this point into a shape in the air.
For more ways to use this 3D pen,
you can go to Bilibili and watch the live broadcast in October 2025.
Later, our little C will also put the live link in the comments section.
We just need to use this editing tool to make some adjustments to it.
After the adjustment is complete,
we can turn it on.
Turn it into a flat version.
As you can see,
the flat version here is flat.
Using this 3D pen,
the line drawing pen function can be completed
from design construction to clothing production.
Next,
we use a牛仔 fabric for this dress.
We can directly search in the cool fabric
and drag it to the app.
OK,
then we can start the 2025.1 version.
Our software is built into the preset of the cow's water washing effect.
After selecting the fabric,
we can switch this to a single cloth.
The water washing,
the speed of the entire water wash is related to the size of our pattern.
Then,
after selecting the fabric,
we can change this to a single cloth.
Then,
we can select this.
Well,
in the other page,
we can change the different silica washing and products
to filmed different filet-filet's effects.
We configured bakingä,
b также øä,
mondä,
süä,
dreme,
b молä,
escine те Ec היא
In this water washing,
the corresponding water-optic ratio value can be monitored.
You can adjust water-opticен dy mainly
and get the real filet effect.
Next, we can add a cowhide edge effect to the lower part of the hair.
You can directly draw a long strip of hair.
Of course, you can also draw the inside line and then cut and sew it in a new piece of fabric.
In addition, in the fabric, we can switch it to a hair style.
From the 2025 version, we can directly show the hair effect at the front window.
We switch the hair type to a cowhide edge.
At the bottom, we can set the length, thickness, density, etc. of the hair.
You can adjust the parameter value of the hair by adjusting the hair's
visibility adjustment.
OK, we have finished this piece of clothing.
The above is all the content I shared today.
Welcome everyone to experience our new 2026.0 version.
New features, bright lights, and bright colors.
The video will be uploaded on April 20th on Bilibili.
The video will be uploaded on May 6th on Bilibili.
Thank you for watching.